# Lekhraj dewangan

Near Brookfield mall, Brookfield, Bangalore

• Contact No: 8123482425 • Email: lekhraj9191@gmail.com

# **Objective**

Waiting for challenging position on new organization where i can learn, earn and delivered my knowledge. Having 2 year experience of Software Automation testing on Linux platform with skills of Debugging and Testing in Telecom and Networking Domain(NGIN platform) with skills on CAP, INAP, Diameter Protocols and its all Messages like IDP, RRBE, AC, ACR, CCR, CCA etc. Mostly involved in Provisioning related interface development based on SOAP. Having basic knowledge of Unix, SQL.

## **Education Details**

• BE, SSITM, bhilai, chhattisgarh

74.2

2014

• HSS(10+2), Govt higher Secondary school, Saja, Chhattisgarh

90

2010

• SSC(10th), Govt. M. H. S. School, Saja, Chhattisgarh

79.5

2008

## **Work Experience**

• Huawei technology India private limited ( client of IKYA human capital solution)

Associate software engineer

Mar 2015 - till date

java developer for telecom domain, SOAP releated interface design for VPN & NTS product on NGIN platform

Infosys

Trainee

Oct 2015 - Feb 2016

Attained IT Spark Training, there i got good knowledge core Java and basic knowledge of JSP, Servalet, JSF, Spring, Database, SQL, Linux,

# **Project Details**

### PROJECT: 1

• Hongkong Heji (for RTCC product)

Developed Small Provisioning Feature called MVR(Mobile Voice Recording) on existing RTCC system. Mostly in this project invalved for Service call flow checking on CAP and INAP protocol to check impact on existing feature over new feature.

Period: july 2016- till now Team Size: 15

Role: Developer

### PROJECT: 2

• Maxico telephonica (VPN Product)

Its Change Requirement Project, where we Replace INAP CS1+ to RO+ (diameter)Protocol to Communicate NGIN with OCS(online changing system).Got Basic knowledge on Diameter protocol and its Messages like, CCR\_I,CCA\_I,CCR\_T,CCA\_T etc.Site support for installation and ATP Testing

Period: june2016-Till now Team Size: 10

Role: Tester

#### PROJECT: 3

• STC-Saudi Telecom company (Clock service & Number Change Notification (NCN) Service

Developed Some SOAP feature like Access Code, Day time configuration, SubService Number etc.

Period: Mar 2016 - May 2016 Team Size: 15

Role: Developer

#### PROJECT: 4

• Belgacom Belgium (VPN product)

Performed core Java Development for particular Provisioning features like Add Member, Destination Number, ADR (Create, delete, Modify, List Operation) etc on SOAP based. Excuted Performance test for Complete SOAP feature to find out Defined Response time on Particular CAP.

Period: Jan 2016 - Till Now Team Size: 30

Role: Developer

#### PROJECT: 5

• Pakistan telecom company limited {NTS}

Successfully Tested Data Migration script from Old Intelligent network system to New Intelligent Network system(ENIP Platform) . Successfully Executed and tested all service calls and verify all site data on New Intelligent N/w system and during Migration find out Major defects. Besides that developed some service related features Core java. Made all configurations of Service switching point , service controlling point, SMP, SMAP, components of ENIP Platform. Supported site during Installation and Execution of calls on site Test bed and Live system.

Period: Nov 2015 - Dec 2015 Team Size: 4

Role: Tester

### PROJECT: 6

• Chile Nextel (VPN Product)

Its Change Requirement Project, Performed core Java Development for some small changes as per requirements.

Period: Sept 2015-OCT 2015 Team Size: 5

Role: Developer

#### PROJECT: 7

• Brazil Claro Telefonica (VPN product)

Performed Java Development for particular Provisioning features like Enterprise, Member, Holiday, Access Code(Create, delete, Modify, List Operation) etc on SOAP based. During development. Also Analysis CDR(Charge detail record), log and Installed and Configured Intelligent Network Components. Supported site during Installation and Execution of calls on site Testbed and Live system.

Period: March 2015-OCT 2015 Team Size: 20

Role: Developer

#### PROJECT: 8

• Peru TLF - Top Up rechage

it small feature to recharge Fixed phone

Period: Dec2016- Jan2017 Team Size: 10

Role: Tested and Automated complete TopUp call flow and integrated in CI machine

### PROJECT: 9

Uruguay PPS service

It handover project for further support and maintenance.

Period: Feb2017-Till Now Team Size: 5

Role: Tested and Automated complete Number analysis part and Prepared ATP document.

## **Field of Interests**

• Information technology, Telecommunications, JAVA Development, Big Data, Hadoop, Data science

## **Skills**

• Java, Unix, Python, Oracle Database, Automation Testing, SOAP Testing using SOAP UI

# **Strength & Hobbies**

- Dedication, Always ready for New things, hard work, excellent & quick Learning skills
- Hunger and fully dedicated to learn new things

### **Declaration**

I hear by declare that the information finished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 01-03-2017 Place: Bangalore